Lucas Brown - Pipeline TD

www.ImLucasBrown.com | (747)-221-4849 | <u>ImLucasBrown@gmail.com</u> vimeo.com/319548283

SUMMARY

Pipeline TD/Technical artist with experience in full stack Python development, pipeline backend/tools, rigging, Pixar USD, and motion capture for animation and games. Expandable and easily deployable systems are king. Motivated and excited to work with supervisors, artists, and programmers to create a well oiled, easy to use, CG pipeline.

EXPERIENCE

Pipeline TD - Sunrise Productions (Contract)

2019-Present

- ➤ Full stack Python developer
 - Lead developer on "NXT" Node exectuion Tree.
 - Node base, layered, code composition application.
 - Qt UI Framework.
 - RPC/IPC for linear code execution in multiple DCCs.
- Pipeline backend development
 - CLI tools for asset creation.
 - Python API/entry points for use by front end devs.
- Interfacing Pixar USD with NXT

RIGGING/TECHNICAL ARTIST - PRETTY SIMPLE GAMES

2017-2019

- Character, vehicle, and prop rigs for mobile game (mGear/custom tools)
- Developing motion capture workflows/tools (Xsens/Ikinema)
- Animation tools
 - o FBX exporter, pickers, and various workflow tools

TECHNICAL ARTIST - SVAD PRODUCTIONS (CONTRACT)

2017-2017

- Rigged creatures for a VR proof of concept.
- Expanded existing Python and MEL codebase for an in house geometry caching plugin.
- Refactored legacy code to support newer versions of Maya.

Media Production Specialist - Southern Adventist University

2013-2016

- Video editing and CG scene creation for short educational videos.
- Project management, pre-production, production, post-production for promotional and educational videos.

Skills - Previous Roles - Programming Languages

- ➤ Maya (PyMel, cmds, OpenMaya)
- > Python
- > Qt Framework
- \succ Rigging
- ➤ Mocap Retargetting

- ➤ git
- CG Pipeline
 - dev/planning/maintenance
- ➤ Cross platform development
 - Linux, OSX, Windows
- > pyenv, conda, direnv, pip

EDUCATION

B.S. Effects Animation COLLEGEDALE, TN USA.

2013 - 2017